there are several other properties in
for tolerance in addition to
dependability one of them is reliability
and unlike dependability which is the
property of the system that we can trust
it to perform its function reliability
is actually something we can measure to
measure reliability we consider the
system to always be in one of these two
states the normal state is the service
accomplishment state so the system is
providing the service that we wanted to
provide the other state is service
interruption so this is at this time the
service is not providing it's not
accomplishing the service that we expect
from it so reliability can now be
defined by measuring continuous service
accomplishment a typical measure for
reliability is mean time to failure or
MTTF and that basically is how long do
we have service accomplishment before we
get into the next service interruption
so it's not enough for example that over
the past two years the system has been
in service accomplishing for one year if
we have a system that accomplishes
service for a month then is interrupted
for a month then accomplishes service
again because it's been fixed then it's
again interrupted for a month in that
case the mean time to failure will be
one month that's how long you have of
continuous service accomplishment on
average between periods of service
interruption another popular metric
related to this is the availability
availability measures service
accomplishment as a fraction of overall
time so reliability measures how long do
we get service accomplishment until the
next failure availability measures what
percentage of time were we in the
service accomplishment state so if the
system on average was half in this state
and half in this state then availability
will be 50% 50% of the time the system
was accomplishing service but
reliability will be on average
how long each of these accomplishment
states lasted until we saw the
interruption so for example if you have
one year of service followed by one year
of service interruption you get 50% here
you get one year here if you get one
month at a time for two years you get
50% here but you get one month here
instead of a year so for availability in
addition to the mean time to failure we
need to know the mean time to repair or
empty TR so this is once the system has
service interruption how long does it
last until it goes back to the service
accomplishment state and then our
availability is the mean time to failure
how long did it function properly at the
time divided by the overall time which
was the mean time to failure plus the
mean time to repair after that you're
back in the accomplishment state so this
is how long we had both service
accomplishment and service interruption
and this is just the service
accomplishment